{"questions":[{"question": "Which one is the capital of Morocco?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Fes/Rabat/Casablanca/Marrakech", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "The four main divisions of philosophy are metaphysics, epistomology, axiology and ...", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Bioethics/Logic/Aesthetics/Categorical logic", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which river flows through Egypt?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Volga/Nile/Amazon/Rhine", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the brain of the computer?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Keyboard/Monitor/CPU/Hard drive", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What does RAM stand for?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Read access memory/Run access memory/Random access memory/Random allocation memory", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which was the name of Aphrodite Child's first album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "End Of The World/666/Reflection/It's Five O'Clock", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What year did Yes release their debut album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "1973/1971/1974/1969", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which letter is silent in the word 'solemn'?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "m/s/n/l", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "We are at about 4000 BC, looking for the original speakers of Indo-European. What area would be the best place to look?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Iberian Peninsula/Northern India/Anatolian plateau/Eurasian steppes", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of these former languages in Italy is not considered to be an Indo-European language?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "South Picene/Etruscan/Umbrian/Oscan", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of those is not an album by Premiata Forneria Marconi?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Storia di un minuto/Io sono nato libero/Per un amico/L'isola di niente", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which modern-day country did the Inca Empire exist?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Venezuela/Mexico/Peru/Guatemala", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'Catch-22' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Vladimir Nabokov/Joseph Heller/Kurt Vonnegut/Cassandra Clare", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which British band released the album 'Parachutes' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Radiohead/Pulp/Coldplay/Oasis", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Tegucigalpa is the capital city of which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Nicaragua/Guatemala/El Salvador/Honduras", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "When was the partition between India and Pakistan?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "1763/1891/1999/1947", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which English rock band released the song 'Pinball Wizard' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Deep Purple/Led Zeppelin/The Who/The Kinks", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The countries of Belgium, Netherlands, and Luxembourg are together called _______ .", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Nethiumberg/Benelux/Luxelneth/Benengium", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the capital of Chad?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Luanda/N'djamena/Bangui/Yaounde", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'Man is born free, but is everywhere in chains' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Ludwig Wittgenstein/Jean-Paul Sartre/Jean-Jacques Rousseau/Baruch de Spinoza", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Who wrote \"The Great Gatsby\" ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Joseph Heller/Ray Bradbury/Harper Lee/F. Scott Fitzgerald", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What did British Honduras change its name to in 1973?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Barbados/Guatemala/Jamaica/Belize", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which US state is divided into two parts by a large lake?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Ohio/Michigan/Wisconsin/Minnesota", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which English heavy metal band released the album 'The Number of the Beast' ?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Black Sabbath/Judas Priest/Mot\u00f6rhead/Iron Maiden", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which is a measure of computer performance in intensive calculations?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "POSIX/FLOPS/ECOS/GIGO", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "When creating a website, what is one of the things, CSS allows you to do?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Database queries/Adjust font size/Copy to clipboard/Attach event listener", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which sequence get elements closer to each other as it progresses?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Arithmetic sequence/Cauchy sequence/Mersenne primes/Fibonacci sequence", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the range of this dataset: {7,9,17,6,8}?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "9/6/11/8", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the second note of the major G scale?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "F#/A/E/C", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is a common method for training artificial neural networks?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Backpropagation/Vertex enumeration/Gauss-Jordan elimination/Hessenberg expansion", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'The Lord of the Rings'?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "G. K. Chesterton/C. S. Lewis/Philip Pullman/J. R. R. Tolkien", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'One cannot step twice in the same river' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Ludwig Wittgenstein/Denis Diderot/Heraclitus/Baruch de Spinoza", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "If a mathematical function is both -injective and surjective-, it is...", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "bijective/superjective/intersubjective/perijective", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "The Occitan language is spoken in certain parts of Southern ... ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Iran/France/Mexico/Russia", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What transforms high level source code into assembly or machine code?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "embedder/abstracter/decoder/compiler", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the second largest state in the USA?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Florida/Texas/California/Oregon", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which album cover did Andy Warhol design for the Rolling Stones?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Exile on Main St/Beggars Banquet/Let it Bleed/Sticky Fingers", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of these countries border Russia?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Kyrgyzstan/North Korea/Uzbekistan/Tajikistan", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "A technique in the construction of large language models is RLHF, which stands for Reinforcement Learning from ... ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Heuristic Factorials/Hypergeometric Faces/Hidden Frequencies/Human Feedback", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Euler's number (e) is the base of ... ?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Natural logarithms/Complex logarithms/Imaginary logarithms/Rational logarithms", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which method can be used to predict the probability of one out of two possible outcomes, based on one or more variables?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Logistic regression/Linear regression/Chi-squared test/Dynamic scaling", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "The language 'Egyptian Arabic' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Austronesian/Dravidian/Afroasiatic/Uralic", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which city is the most populated in South Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Johannesburg/Cape Town/Pretoria/Durban", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2003?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Lost in Translation/Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World/The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King/Mystic River", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which song was originally recorded by Joni Mitchell and was later covered by Crosby, Stills, Nash & Young?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Carry On/Always Cut My Hair/Woodstock/Our House", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Gaborone is the capital city of which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Malawi/Lesotho/Eswatini/Botswana", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which philosopher famously said 'It is wrong always, everywhere and for everyone, to believe anything upon insufficient evidence' ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Aristoteles/W. K. Clifford/Friedrich Nietzsche/Ludwig Wittgenstein", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which film contains the character 'Inspector Jacques Clouseau' ?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Pink Panther/The Treasure of the Sierra Madre/Apocalypse Now/Fargo", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "The language 'Hindi' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Indo-European/Austronesian/Uralic/Dravidian", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "'Finding Nemo' was released in which year?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "1997/2003/2000/2006", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which author wrote 'Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Oscar Wilde/Robert Louis Stevenson/Agatha Christie/Joseph Conrad", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Who wrote 'The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy' ?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "John Grisham/Douglas Adams/Stephen King/Terry Pratchett", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "The language 'Hausa' belongs to which language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Austronesian/Niger-Congo/Dravidian/Afroasiatic", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "How are domestic canines more commonly known?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Cows/Wolves/Dogs/Foxes", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Golden Earring had which hit single in 1973?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Eight Miles High/Radar Love/No For An Answer/Long Blond Animal", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which year was the Beatles' \"Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band\" released?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "1966/1968/1967/1965", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is phonetics concerned with?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Meaning/Writing/Sounds/Grammar", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Who was considered the 'Father of Linguistics', a Swiss guy, who authored the seminal book entitled 'Course in General Linguistics' ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "William James/Noam Chomsky/Leonard Bloomfield/Ferdinand de Saussure", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What animals can breathe \"with their cheeks\" ?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Insects/Amphibians/Birds/Mammals", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Arabic belongs to the ...", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Semitic languages/Berber languages/Turkic languages/Nubian languages", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the derivative of f(x)=sin(x) ?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "-cos(x)/cot(x)/cos(x)/tan(x)", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which is a synonym of 'penitent' ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "impolite/contrite/diffident/candent", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What can be a possible cause for packet loss in the Internet ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Checksum is in binary/Receive window too large/Phishing attack/Network congestion", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the largest species of shark?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Whale Shark/Hammerhead Shark/Great White Shark/Tiger Shark", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which animal is known for its ability to change color to blend into its surroundings?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Chameleon/Peacock/Octopus/Flamingo", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the primary defense mechanism of a skunk?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Camouflage/Loud screeching/Spraying a foul-smelling liquid/Playing dead", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "How many species of skunks are there?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "2/12/4/10", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What does \"CPU\" stand for in computer terminology?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Central Power Unit/Control Program Utility/Central Processing Unit/Computer Personal Unit", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which programming language is primarily used for web development on the client side?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "C++/Java/JavaScript/Python", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In computer networking, what does the term \"latency\" refer to?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The maximum bandwidth available in a network/The amount of data transmitted over a network/The time it takes for data to travel from the source to the destination/The number of devices connected to a network", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which significant historical event took place in Augsburg in 1555?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Augsburg Peace of Religion/The signing of the Treaty of Augsburg/The establishment of the Augsburg Confession/ The beginning of the Thirty Years' War", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the value of the derivative of the function  \ud835\udc53 ( \ud835\udc65 ) = 3 \ud835\udc65 2 \u2212 5 \ud835\udc65 + 4 f(x)=3x  2  \u22125x+4 at the point  \ud835\udc65 = 2 x=2?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "10/7/5/1", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the fundamental theorem of algebra?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "The sum of the angles in a triangle is 180 degrees. /Every polynomial equation of degree n has exactly n roots in the complex number system./The product of the roots of a polynomial is equal to the constant term./Every polynomial can be factored into linear factors.", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the profession of the character Sean Maguire, played by Robin Williams, in Good Will Hunting?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Professor/Psychologist/Mathematician/Carpenter", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the primary focus of the film My Own Private Idaho?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The journey of two friends who are also hustlers./The life of a successful businessman./A family's struggle with mental illness./A road trip across America for a music festival.", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following films is directed by Alejandro Gonz\u00e1lez I\u00f1\u00e1rritu?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Babel/All of the above/Birdman/The Revenant", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What major event took place in Algeria from 1954 to 1962?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Algerian Civil War/The Battle of Algiers/The establishment of the Algerian Republic/The Algerian War of Independenc", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What language family does Tigrinya belong to?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Niger-Congo/Indo-European/Afro-Asiatic/Sino-Tibetan", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What was the significance of the Battle of Adwa in 1896 for Ethiopia?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "It secured Ethiopian sovereignty against Italian invasion./It marked the end of the Ethiopian Civil War./ It led to the establishment of the Ethiopian Empire./ It was the first time Ethiopia was colonized.", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was the title of King Crimson's debut album released in 1969?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Larks' Tongues in Aspic/Red/In the Court of the Crimson King/Discipline", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following novels is considered David Foster Wallace's magnum opus?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Girl with Curious Hair/Infinite Jest/The Broom of the System/Brief Interviews with Hideous Men", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which prestigious award did Elfriede Jelinek receive in 2004?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Nobel Prize in Literature/Pulitzer Prize/Goethe Prize/Booker Prize", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was the significance of Ravenna during the Roman Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "It was the location of the Colosseum./It was the birthplace of Julius Caesar. /It served as the main naval base of the Roman fleet./It was the capital of the Western Roman Empire.", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following philosophers is most commonly associated with existentialism?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Jean-Paul Sartre/Karl Marx/Immanuel Kant/Friedrich Nietzsche", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is Gottlob Frege primarily known for in the field of philosophy?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Establishing the concept of the unconscious/Founding modern logic and philosophy of language/Introducing existentialism/Developing the theory of relativity", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which concept is most closely associated with Horkheimer and Adorno in their critique of culture and society?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The \"Social Contract\"/The \"Culture Industry\"/Pragmatism/Crisis of Meaning", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the main theme of Rousseau's work The Social Contract?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The importance of individual freedom and the general will/The inevitability of social inequality/The necessity of absolute monarchy/The rejection of private property", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the primary diet of raccoons (Procyon lotor)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Herbivorous, primarily feeding on plants/Insectivorous, primarily feeding on insects/Carnivorous, primarily feeding on other animals/Omnivorous, eating both plant and animal matter", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is a unique reproductive feature of seahorses (Hippocampus)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "The males carry and incubate the eggs in a pouch./They have a symbiotic relationship with other fish for reproduction./They reproduce asexually. /They lay eggs in a nest.", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is one of the most distinctive social behaviors of bonobos (Pan paniscus)?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "They primarily use tools for foraging. /They exhibit strong male dominance hierarchies./They are strictly solitary animals./They use sexual behavior to resolve conflicts and strengthen social bonds.", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What major event occurred in the Democratic Republic of the Congo in 1960?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The establishment of Belgian colonial rule/The first democratic elections/The Congo Crisis and the declaration of independence from Belgium/The rise of Mobutu Sese Seko to power", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following works is written by Dimitri Verhulst?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "The Misfortunates/The Discovery of Heaven/The Book of Chameleons/The Sorrow of Belgium", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the primary reason for the hibernation of dormice (Gliridae), commonly known as \"Siebenschl\u00e4fer\"?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "To survive food scarcity during winter/To migrate to warmer climates/To avoid predators/To enter a mating period", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following mechanisms do Venus flytraps (Dionaea muscipula) use to capture their prey?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Passive trapping/Pitfall trapping/Snap trapping/Adhesive trapping", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which novel is J.D. Salinger best known for, featuring the character Holden Caulfield?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Catcher in the Rye/Raise High the Roof Beam, Carpenter/Nine Stories/Franny and Zooey", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the scientific name for the giant sequoia, commonly known as the mammoth tree?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Taxodium distichum/Sequoiadendron giganteum/Sequoia sempervirens/Metasequoia glyptostroboides", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following novels was written by Clemens J. Setz?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Indigo/The Floating Theatre/The Hour of the Star/The Invention of Morel", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the primary purpose of eigenvalues and eigenvectors in linear algebra?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "To calculate the determinant of a matrix/To solve systems of equations/To analyze linear transformations and their effects on vector spaces/To determine the rank of a matrix", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following distributions is characterized by its bell-shaped curve and is commonly used in statistics?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Poisson distribution/Exponential distribution/Normal distribution/Binomial distribution", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following novels is written by Tahar Ben Jelloun?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "The Invisible Man/This Blinding Absence of Light/The Name of the Rose/The Sand Child", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following authors is known for their significant contributions to Maghrebian literature?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Naguib Mahfouz/Gabriel Garc\u00eda M\u00e1rquez/Assia Djebar/Mario Vargas Llosa", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "When was Heidelberg University founded?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "1750/1600/1453/1386", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Who wrote the famous poem \"Heidelberg\" and visited the city several times in the 19th century?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Heinrich Heine/Mark Twain/Friedrich Schiller/Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which movie did Matt Damon portray an astronaut stranded on Mars?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Elysium/Gravity/Interstellar/The Martian", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the name of the famous street depicted in Fellini's La Dolce Vita?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Via Condotti/Via Appia/Via Veneto/Via del Corso", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following films is a political satire directed by Nanni Moretti?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "La Messa \u00e8 Finita/Mia Madre/Il Caimano/Caro Diario", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Zabriskie Point is famous for its final sequence. What happens during this scene?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "A car chase through the desert/A protest turns violent/The protagonists escape to Mexico/A house explodes in slow motion", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the main theme of Ken Park?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Drug addiction and recovery/Urban crime and corruption/Teenage alienation and dysfunctional families/Political activism and rebellion", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which character is an undercover cop infiltrating the Irish mob in The Departed?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Sean Dignam/Frank Costello/Billy Costigan/Colin Sullivan", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the meaning of the standard deviation in a dataset?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The range of the dataset/The measure of the spread or dispersion of the data/The average of the data points/The square of the mean", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the determinant of a square matrix used to determine?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The eigenvalues of the matrix/Whether the matrix is invertible/The rank of the matrix/The trace of the matrix", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the main focus of Wittgenstein's early work, Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The nature of time/Ethics and morality/The existence of God/Language and its relation to reality", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the primary concern of linguistic philosophy?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The classification of languages/The history of language development/The study of phonetics and grammar/The relationship between language, thought, and reality", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is Giambattista Vico's view on the nature of human history?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "History is solely determined by economic factors/History is completely random and lacks any discernible order/History is linear and progresses towards a specific goal/History is cyclical and characterized by recurring themes and patterns", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which philosopher proposed the idea that history is a struggle between the ruling class and the oppressed class?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Michel Foucault/Alexis de Tocqueville/Max Weber/Karl Marx", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What significant event occurred in 711 AD that impacted the history of Andalusia?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The discovery of America/The establishment of the Spanish Inquisition/The Reconquista/The arrival of the Moors and the beginning of Muslim rule", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which event in 1979 dramatically changed the political landscape of Iran?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Constitutional Revolution/The Islamic Revolution/The Iran-Iraq War/The Anglo-Persian War", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What was the Aksum Empire primarily known for?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Its conquests of neighboring territories/Its vast collection of written literature/Its naval power and exploration/Its advanced agricultural techniques and trade networks", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following empires is associated with the rise of Timbuktu as a prominent city?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Ottoman Empire/The Roman Empire/The Byzantine Empire/The Mali Empire", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Timbuktu is located in which present-day country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Mali/Senegal/Nigeria/Burkina Faso", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was the capital of the Byzantine Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Alexandria/Rome/Constantinople/Athens", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is a neural network?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "A hardware component of a computer/A computational model inspired by the way biological neural networks in the human brain process information/A network of interconnected computers/A type of computer virus", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which novel is based on Thomas Mann's own family background and examines the decline of a wealthy merchant family?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Magic Mountain/Confessions of Felix Krull/The Holy Sinner/Buddenbrooks", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In which city was Goethe born?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Stuttgart/Berlin/Frankfurt am Main/Weimar", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Sloths are known for their slow metabolism. Approximately how long can it take for a sloth to digest food?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "12-24 hours/2-3 hours/30-40 hours/1-2 weeks", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What family do dogs, wolves, and foxes belong to?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Mustelidae/Canidae/Ursidae/Felidae", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Domestic pigs are known for their intelligence. Which of the following animals are they often compared to in terms of cognitive abilities?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Cats/Cows/Horses/Dogs", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What does \"open\" software mean?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Software that is only available online/Software whose source code is available for modification and distribution/Software that is free of charge/Software that requires a license", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which sorting algorithm is known for its efficiency in large datasets and is commonly implemented in many programming languages?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Selection Sort/Quick Sort/Insertion Sort/Bubble Sort", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following is a fundamental data structure in computer science used to store a collection of items?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "All of the above/Tree/Array/Graph", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which philosophical tradition is Hegel associated with?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Rationalism/Idealism/Existentialism/Empiricism", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the title of Spinoza's most significant work, where he presents his philosophical ideas on God, nature, and ethics?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Ethics/Theological-Political Treatise/Axioms of Religion/Tractatus Politicus", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Meister Eckhart was a prominent figure in which philosophical and theological tradition?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Rationalism/Christian Mysticism/Scholasticism/Sufism", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the definition of a limit in the context of calculus?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The area under a curve./The highest value of a function./The value that a function approaches as the input approaches a certain point./The rate of change of a function. ", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a normal distribution?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "It has two peaks./It is uniform./It is skewed to the right./It has a mean, median, and mode that are all equal.", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In calculus, what does the derivative of a function represent?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The average rate of change of the function./The area under the curve of the function./The instantaneous rate of change of the function./The maximum value of the function.", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following is one of Camille Saint-Sa\u00ebns's most famous works?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Nutcracker Suite/The Four Seasons/Carnival of the Animals/The Rite of Spring", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which instrument did John Coltrane play?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Trumpet/Saxophone/Trombone/Piano", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Holst composed \"The Planets\" between 1914 and 1917. How many movements are in this suite?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "8/7/9/5", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which film did Woody Allen win an Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Match Point/Crimes and Misdemeanors/Hannah and Her Sisters/Annie Hall", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following films is directed by Pedro Almod\u00f3var?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Talk to Her/Am\u00e9lie/Pan's Labyrinth/The Sea Inside", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following films directed by Herzog features a narrative about the construction of an opera house in the Amazon rainforest?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Fitzcarraldo/Nosferatu/Stroszek/My Best Fiend", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Thomas Bernhard often criticized which aspect of Austrian culture in his writings?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Environmental issues/Nationalism and conformity/The education system/The arts", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the title of Hemingway's novella that tells the story of an old fisherman and his struggle with a giant marlin?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Old Man and the Sea/The Snows of Kilimanjaro/Islands in the Stream/A Moveable Feast", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the study of the rules governing the structure of sentences in a language called?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Semantics/Morphology/Pragmatics/Syntax", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In phonetics, what is the term for the smallest unit of sound that can distinguish meaning in a language?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Grapheme/Morpheme/Allophone/Phoneme", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which theory posits that the structure of a language influences its speakers' worldview or cognition?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Relativity Hypothesis (Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis)/Generative Grammar/Universal Grammar/Structuralism", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the approximate length of the Niger River, making it one of the longest rivers in Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "5800 kilometers/2600 kilometers/4200 kilometers/1600 kilometers", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The Danube Delta, a UNESCO World Heritage site, is located in which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Serbia/Bulgaria/Hungary/Romania", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following countries shares a border with Niger?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Algeria/All of the above/Nigeria/Mali", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which city, known as a center of learning and trade, was part of the Mali Empire?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Lagos/Timbuktu/Cairo/Marrakech", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What was the primary military tactic used by the Mongol armies that contributed to their success?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Guerrilla warfare/Fast cavalry and mobility/Siege warfare/Naval warfare", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following cat breeds is known for being hairless?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Siamese/Sphynx/Persian/Maine Coon", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of these North American animals is known for its role in shaping river ecosystems by building dams?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "American Bison/North American Beaver/Gray Wolf/Grizzly Bear", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In the context of database management, what does the acronym ACID stand for?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Availability, Concurrency, Integrity, Deletion/Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability/Asynchronous, Centralized, Inverse, Denormalized/Authorization, Compression, Inference, Distribution", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which algorithmic paradigm does the Dijkstra's algorithm for shortest paths primarily rely on?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Dynamic Programming/Greedy Algorithm/Backtracking/Divide and Conquer", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which is the longest mountain range in Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Atlas Mountains/Rwenzori Mountains/Drakensberg Mountains/Simien Mountains", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the world highest mountain?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Kilimanjaro/Mount Everest/Denali/K2", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which empire was known for its extensive trade networks and cultural exchanges during the early modern period in India?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Maurya Empire/Gupta Empire/Chola Dynasty/Mughal Empire", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which civilization is known for its advanced architectural achievements and the creation of the calendar, and was prominent in Mexico before the Spanish conquest?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Maya/Inca/Olmec/Aztec", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following language families includes languages such as Russian, Polish, and Czech?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Semitic/Romance/Slavic/Germanic", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the primary characteristic that defines a language as belonging to the Sino-Tibetan language family?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "It uses an alphabetic writing system./ It includes only languages spoken in China./It has no grammatical structure./It is tonal and primarily spoken in East Asia.", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which theorem states that every continuous function on a closed interval attains its maximum and minimum values?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Bolzano-Weierstrass Theorem/Intermediate Value Theorem/Mean Value Theorem/Extreme Value Theorem", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which theorem provides a method for approximating the value of a function using its derivatives at a single point?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Fundamental Theorem of Calculus/Taylor's Theorem/Pythagorean Theorem/L'H\u00f4pital's Rule", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the central theme of Pedro Almod\u00f3var's film \"Todo sobre mi madre\" (All About My Mother)?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The impact of war on families/The search of a lost child/The complexities of motherhood and identity/The challenges of aging", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which Alfred Hitchcock film features a character named Marion Crane, who becomes the victim of a notorious shower scene?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Rear Window/Psycho/North By Northwest/Vertigo", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is a primary characteristic that distinguishes heavy metal music from hard rock?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Inclusion of acoustic instruments/Emphasis on melodic hooks/Heavier guitar riffs and darker themes/Use of clean vocals", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which Focus album, released in 1971, features the hit single \"Hocus Pocus\"?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Focus III/Moving Waves/Hamburger Concerto/Live at the Rainbow", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which philosopher is known for the statement \"I think, therefore I am\"?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Immanuel Kant/Friedrich Nietzsche/John Locke/Ren\u00e9 Descartes", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Schelling primarily associated with, emphasizing the idea of nature as a dynamic and self-revealing process?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Philosophy of Nature/Dialectical Materialism/Transcendental Idealism/Absolute Idealism", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What scientific suborder does the family Hyaenidae belong to ?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Haplorhini/Feliformia/Caniformia/Ciconiiformes", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the scientific name of the cheetah?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Felis catus/Panthera onca/Acinonyx jubatus/Lynx rufus", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What bird is born with claws on its wing digits?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Secretary bird/Cormorant/Cassowary/Hoatzin", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of these is not a layer in the OSI model for data communications?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Transport Layer/Physical Layer/Connection Layer/Application Layer", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What port does HTTP run on?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "80/53/23/443", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What does the International System of Quantities refer 1024 bytes as?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Kelobyte/Kilobyte/Kylobyte/Kibibyte", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of these is NOT a real tectonic plate?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Nazca Plate/Eurasian Plate/Atlantic Plate/North American Plate", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the most populous Muslim-majority nation in 2010?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Saudi Arabia/Sudan/Indonesia/Iran", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "How many countries border Kyrgyzstan?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "3/1/4/6", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The Second Boer War in 1899 was fought where?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "South Africa/Nepal/Argentina/Bulgaria", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which day did World War I begin?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "July 28/January 28/April 28/June 28", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "How many women joined the United States Armed Services during World War II?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "500000/100000/350000/250000", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the approximate value of mathematical constant e?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "2.72/3.14/1.41/1.62", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the smallest number that can be expressed as the sum of two positive cubes in two different ways?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "4104/561/1729/91", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "The decimal number 31 in hexadecimal would be what?", "category": "Mathematics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "3D/2E/1B/1F", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In which African country was the 2006 film 'Blood Diamond' mostly set in?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Central African Republic/Burkina Faso/Liberia/Sierra Leone", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was the first feature-length computer-animated movie?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "101 Dalmatians/Toy Story/Lion king/Tron", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Who directed \"E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial\" (1982)?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Stanley Kubrick/James Cameron/Tim Burton/Steven Spielberg", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Who was the guitarist in the band \"The Doors\"?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Jim Morrison/Ray Manzarek/John Densmore/Robby Krieger", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What was the name of Pink Floyd's first studio album?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Piper at the Gates of Dawn/More/Ummagumma/Atom Heart Mother", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What was The Velvet Underground's first album called?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "White Light-White Heat/The Velvet Underground/Loaded/The Velvet Underground & Nico", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which author co-wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\" alongside Karl Marx?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Friedrich Engels/Arthur Schopenhauer/Ludwig Wittgenstein/Gottlob Frege", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "The novel \"Of Mice And Men\" was written by what author?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "John Steinbeck/George Orwell/Harper Lee/Mark Twain", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In the year 1818, novelist Mary Shelly is credited with writing a fiction novel and creating this infamous character.", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Dracula/Frankenstein's monster/The Thing/The Invisible Man", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Who wrote the novel \"Moby Dick\"?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "William Shakespeare/J. R. R. Tolkien/Herman Melville/William Golding", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which concept is central to Schopenhauer's philosophy and is described as the driving force behind all life and phenomena?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Will/Being/Knowledge/Reason", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In Thus Spoke Zarathustra, what concept does Nietzsche introduce as a model for personal growth, symbolizing an ideal of strength, creativity, and self-overcoming?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Slave Morality/\u00dcbermensch (Overman)/Eternal Recurrence/Apollonian and Dionysian", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of these languages does not use articles?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Swahili/Italian/Arabic/Turkish", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the term for a speech sound produced without any significant constriction of the airflow in the vocal tract?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Plosive/Vowel/Fricative/Affricate", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In phonetics, which of the following describes a sound made by fully stopping the airflow and then releasing it, as in the sounds /p/ or /t/?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Lateral/Nasal/Approximant/Plosive", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the average age at which women enter menopause?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "~46 years/~64 years/~39 years/~51 years", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "\"hitherto\" means ... ?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "thereupon/in due course/before long/up until now", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which word contains a velar consonant?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "bee/gay/they/lie", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "How many bones does a white shark have in its body?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "56/0/333/216", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What philosopher wrote \"Leviathan\" ?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Karl Popper/John Stuart Mill/Bertrand Russell/Thomas Hobbes", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Deep neural networks are so called, because they have multiple ... ?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Markov chains/Decision trees/Clustered indices/Hidden layers", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which fish spawns in freshwater, but spends its adult life at sea?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Swordfish/Salmon/American eel/Tuna", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which country occupied Albania from 1939 to 1943?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Spain/Yugoslavia/Italy/Romania", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of these pairs of words are antonyms?", "category": "Linguistics", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "congenial-vitrolic/belligerent-pugnacious/destitute-bankrupt/antiquated-archaic", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which is an alternative to gradient descent when constructing artificial neural networks?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Neuroevolution/Huffman coding/Exponential backoff/Marzullo synchronisation", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which network encrypts and passes on data through random relays to ensure Internet anonymity?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Mig/Fub/Jag/Tor", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of these philosophers lived in the 20th century?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Karl Popper/Gottfried Leibniz/Arthur Schopenhauer/Ren\u00e9 Descartes", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following characteristics is unique to the traditional playing style of the Appalachian dulcimer compared to other stringed instruments?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "It is typically held and played flat on the lap./It is played with a bow rather than plucked./It has frets that allow microtonal tuning./It uses double-course strings exclusively", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which of the following bands was a key figure in the \"British Invasion,\" bringing British rock and pop music to the United States in the 1960s?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Rolling Stones/The Beach Boys/Creedence Clearwater Revival/The Byrds", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which music genre is Creedence Clearwater Revival most commonly associated with, blending rock and roll with Southern, blues, and country influences?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Folk Rock/Southern Rock/Psychedelic Rock/Swamp Rock", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following novels by John Irving tells the story of a writer reflecting on his life, love, and the influence of wrestling?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Last Night in Twisted River/The World According to Garp/The Cider House Rules/A Prayer for Owen Meany", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which film series did Tobey Maguire gain widespread fame for portraying a character with superhuman abilities and a strong sense of responsibility?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "The Lord of the Rings/Spider-Man/The Matrix/X-Men", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In which critically acclaimed film did River Phoenix portray a group of boys who go on a journey to find their missing friend, ultimately confronting issues of friendship and loss?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Stand By Me/The Thing Called Love/Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade/The River Wild", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "In Into the Wild, which real-life figure does Emile Hirsch portray, who abandons his possessions and embarks on a journey across America to live in the Alaskan wilderness?", "category": "Movies", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Jack Kerouac/Christopher McCandless/John Muir/Henry David Thoreau", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which novel by Jack Kerouac is considered a defining work of the Beat Generation, chronicling a series of spontaneous road trips across the United States?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Big Sur/The Dharma Bums/Visions of Cody/On the Road", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which philosophical theme is central to Thoreau's Walden, emphasizing self-reliance and individualism in the face of societal pressures?", "category": "Philosophy", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Naturalism/Realism/Transcendentalism/Romanticism", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which novel by William Burroughs is considered a landmark work of the Beat Generation, known for its experimental narrative style and themes of addiction and control?", "category": "Literature", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Junk/Naked Lunch/On the Road/Soft Machine", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following bands is most closely associated with the Canterbury Scene, known for its blend of progressive rock and jazz influences?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Genesis/King Crimson/Yes/Soft Machine", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which band is considered the pioneer of the Zeuhl genre, known for its blend of progressive rock, jazz, and a unique rhythmic style, often characterized by repetitive basslines and choral vocals?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Gong/Heldon/Magma/Univers Zero", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "In Frank Zappa's 1970 album Burnt Weeny Sandwich, which track is notable for its jazz influences and features a prominent guitar solo by Zappa?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Peaches en Regalia\"/The Little House I Used to Live In/The Gumbo Variations/Bobby Brown", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which Free song, released in 1970, became one of the band's most famous tracks and is known for its powerful vocals by Paul Rodgers and its iconic guitar riff?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "All Right Now/Wishing Well/Heavy Load/Fire and Water", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which Zucchero song, released in 1987, features a blend of blues and rock influences and is one of his most successful hits, often performed in both Italian and English?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Baila (Sexy Thing)/Il Volo/Diamante\"/Senza una Donna", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which Talking Heads song, released in 1980 and featured on the album Remain in Light, is known for its Afrobeat-inspired rhythms and became one of the band's signature tracks?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Life During Wartime/Burning Down the House/Once in a Lifetime/Psycho Killer", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which piece by Claude Debussy, inspired by a poem by St\u00e9phane Mallarm\u00e9, is considered a turning point in modern music for its use of impressionistic harmonies and orchestration?", "category": "Music", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Pr\u00e9lude \u00e0 l'apr\u00e8s-midi d'un faune/La Mer/Clair de Lune/Images", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which group of animals is known for their ability to regenerate lost body parts, including entire limbs in some cases?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Mammals/Amphibians/Echinoderms/Reptiles", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What is the primary function of xylem tissue in plants?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Photosynthesis/Transporting water and minerals from roots to leaves/Transporting nutrients from leaves to roots/Seed dispersal", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which animal has the longest migration of any mammal, traveling up to 12,000 miles round-trip each year?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Arctic tern/Blue whale/African elephant/Humpback whale", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "What is the primary role of chlorophyll in plants?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "To transport nutrients/To protect the plant from pests/To produce seeds/To absorb sunlight for photosynthesis", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which of the following animals is known for its symbiotic relationship with coral, helping to maintain the health of coral reefs?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Sea urchin/Parrotfish/Clownfish/Moray eel", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which plant hormone is responsible for stimulating cell elongation and growth, particularly in young shoots?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Cytokinin/Ethylene/Gibberellin/Auxin", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which animal group includes species that lay eggs with hard shells and exhibit scales covering their bodies?", "category": "Biology", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Birds/Reptiles/Amphibians/Mammals", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following is an example of a functional programming language that emphasizes immutability and pure functions?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "C++/Java/Python/Haskell", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "In relational databases, which SQL clause is used to specify the condition that must be met for the rows to be returned?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "SELECT/ORDER BY/JOIN/WHERE", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which data structure is best suited for implementing a LIFO (Last In, First Out) ordering?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Tree/Stack/Heap/Queue", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "In database management, what is the purpose of normalization?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "To provide database encryption/To eliminate data redundancy and improve data integrity/To create data backups/To increase the speed of data retrieval", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which algorithm is commonly used for finding the shortest path in a graph with non-negative weights?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Prim\u2019s Algorithm/Dijkstra Algorithm/Bellman-Ford Algorithm/Depth-First Search", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "What is the primary advantage of a balanced binary search tree, such as an AVL or Red-Black tree, over an unbalanced binary search tree?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Faster insertion operations/Guaranteed O(log n) time complexity for search, insert, and delete operations/Simpler implementation/Reduced memory usage", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which of the following algorithms is commonly used for sorting and has an average time complexity of O(n log n)?", "category": "Computer Science", "difficulty": "hard", "points": 30.0, "optString": "Bubble Sort/Insertion Sort/Selection Sort/Merge Sort", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which river is the longest in South America?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Magdalena/Orinoco/Paran\u00e1/Amazon", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Which country has the largest population in Africa?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Nigeria/South Africa/Egypt/Ethiopia", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "What is the name of the mountain range that separates Europe from Asia?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Ural Mountains/Alps/Carpathians/Pyrenees", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which desert is the largest hot desert in the world?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Gobi Desert/Arabian Desert/Sahara Desert/Kalahari Desert", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which European city is known for its canals and is often referred to as the \"Venice of the North\"?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Helsinki/Amsterdam/Stockholm/Copenhagen", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which country is home to the ancient city of Petra, known for its rock-cut architecture?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Egypt/Greece/Turkey/Jordan", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Mount Kilimanjaro, the highest peak in Africa, is located in which country?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Tanzania/Uganda/Ethiopia/Kenya", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "Which is the only continent without a desert?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "North America/South America/Europe/Asia", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which sea is bordered by Jordan, Israel, and Palestine, and is known for being one of the saltiest bodies of water in the world?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Caspian Sea/Mediterranean Sea/Dead Sea/Red Sea", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which of the following countries is landlocked?", "category": "Geography", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Chile/Portugal/Bolivia/Vietnam", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "Which empire was ruled by Genghis Khan and became one of the largest empires in history?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Persian Empire/Mongol Empire/Roman Empire/Ottoman Empire", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Who was the first President of the United States?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "George Washington/Abraham Lincoln/John Adams/Thomas Jefferson", "correctOption": 0}, {"question": "The Hundred Years' War was primarily fought between which two countries?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Spain and England/France and Germany/England and France/Italy and France", "correctOption": 2}, {"question": "What was the name of the ancient trade route that connected China with the Mediterranean, facilitating trade and cultural exchange?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "The Tea Horse Road/The Silk Road/The Amber Road/The Spice Route", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which ancient civilization is credited with the invention of writing, known as cuneiform?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Ancient Egypt/The Greeks/Ancient China/The Sumerians", "correctOption": 3}, {"question": "Who was the British Prime Minister during most of World War II, known for his speeches and leadership?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Neville Chamberlain/Winston Churchill/Harold Macmillan/Clement Attlee", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "The Renaissance, a period of cultural rebirth and intellectual advancement, began in which European country?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "France/Italy/Germany/Spain", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "The Russian Revolution of 1917 led to the rise of which political ideology in Russia?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "easy", "points": 10.0, "optString": "Capitalism/Communism/Monarchy/Fascism", "correctOption": 1}, {"question": "Which French military leader rose to prominence during the French Revolution and later became Emperor of France?", "category": "History", "difficulty": "medium", "points": 20.0, "optString": "Maximilien Robespierre/Napoleon Bonaparte/Louis XVI/Charles de Gaulle", "correctOption": 1}]}
